screenr.com 2019-12-09

# Articulate Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy was last updated effective December 6, 2019.

We are Articulate Global, Inc. ("Articulate") of 244 5th Avenue, Suite 2960, New York, NY 10001, USA. All references to "we", "us", or "our" shall be construed to mean Articulate.

### When We Act as Controller and Processor

Articulate will be acting as the **"Controller"** of the personal data you provide directly to us via a “Contact Us” form, when creating an account, or via other contact methods. You are not required to provide your personal information for purposes of navigating through the public areas of our website.

If you are an employee or an authorized user of one of our customers which have entered into an agreement with us for the provision of our products or services, we will be acting as the **"Processor"** of your personal data transmitted by our customer. Our customer will be acting as Controller of your information. As processor, we do not own, control, or direct the use of any data provided to us by our customers which act as Controllers.

### Personally Identifiable Information

**"Personally Identifiable Information"** (or "PII") refers to contact information that directly or indirectly tells specifically who you are, such as your name, phone number, company name, job, email, postal address, or any other information that could be linked to you with reasonable effort. We do not collect sensitive information such as location information (GPS), racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, or trade union membership, genetic data, biometric data, data concerning health or data concerning a natural person's sex life or sexual orientation.

### Passively or Automatically Collected Data

Passively or automatically collected data (referred to as **"Usage Data"** ) is collected as you use this website. We, our affiliated entities, and our marketing partners may use automated means to collect various types of information about you, your computer or other device used to access this site, its services, related Web applications, and downloadable software. This information is based on your usage of this site and may be based on your visitation to other websites. Usage Data is essentially anonymous when collected, but could be used indirectly to identify a person.

### Why We Need Your Data

We need to know the PII you provide to us directly in our capacity as controller for purposes of responding to your inquiry on our Contact Us web page and other contact methods. In addition, we need to know your PII to send you emails for other specific purposes and for sharing your PII for purposes as described in the Information Sharing and Disclosure section below. We also need to know the PII of authorized users of our customers when we act in our capacity as processor for purposes of managing the authorized use of our services. 

### How We Collect and Use Your Data

Articulate collects PII directly from you when you make an inquiry for an email reply on our “Contact Us” web page and other contact methods, and when you request that we send you emails. Before collecting your PII, you will have the option to give or withhold your consent for our sending you emails including our use of your PII for marketing emails to promote our products or products similar to our products or services. You may withdraw your consent at any time by unsubscribing to our emails by using an opt-out link contained in every non-transactional email or by updating your marketing preferences on your account page.

Articulate uses third-party applications to add firmographic information to the data we collect from you. This data enhancement allows us to provide more helpful, personalized communication.

We collect Usage Data as described above and with “cookies”. For additional information and how to set your browser to refuse to accept “cookies”, see the “COOKIES” section below.

We may make full, unrestricted use of Usage Data for any purpose in our sole discretion, including without limitation, to customize re-marketing ads, offers and content made available to you based on your visits to and/or usage of this site or its services, and to analyze the performance of those ads, offers and content, as well as your interaction with them. 

Subject to your right to opt-out, we may combine Usage Data with PII that we collect, and use the combined data to create profiles about you only for purposes of improving our products and services and your user experience with our products and services.

### How Long We Keep Your Data

We will not retain your PII for longer than required. This means that we will keep your PII for any or a combination of time periods described as follows: (i) for as long as required by law, (ii) until we no longer have a valid reason for keeping it, (iii) until you request us to stop using it, or (iv) for so long as our customer for which you are an authorized user remains a customer. In addition, we retain your Personally Identifiable Information to preserve history in the E-Learning Heroes community and to provide the ongoing ability to participate. When we delete your PII from our databases, it will remain in our backup system until it cycles out.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

General Disclosure Policy. We may share and disclose your PII as described below. We may share and disclose Usage Data without restriction, including without limitation, as described below. Please contact us at [privacy@articulate.com](mailto:privacy@articulate.com) to opt out of all information sharing with a third party.

Affiliated Entities. We may provide your PII and Usage Data to any affiliated entities we may have, including our subsidiaries. Affiliated entities are entities that we legally control (by voting rights) or that control us.

Sub-Processors. We may provide access to your PII and Usage Data to our trusted sub-processors that assist us with the operation and maintenance of this site. For example, we may contract with third parties to process payments, host our servers, provide security, and provide production, fulfillment, optimization, analytics, reporting, and software maintenance and development services. In addition, our sub-processors will be given access to your information only as is reasonably necessary to provide the services for which they are contracted.

Successors. If we sell or otherwise transfer part or all of our business or assets to another organization, such as in the course of an acquisition, merger, bankruptcy or liquidation, we may transfer your PII and Usage Data. In such an event, we will require the buyer or transferee to agree to our commitments provided in this Privacy Policy.

Compelling Obligations. Except for sharing your information as described in this Information Sharing and Disclosure Section, Articulate will not disclose information about you or the contents of your communications unless compelled to do so in the good-faith belief that such action is reasonably necessary (a) to comply with the law; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to enforce these terms and conditions; (d) to respond to claims that any content violates the rights of third parties; (e) to facilitate the terms of an acquisition of Articulate by, or merger with, another company, or (f) to protect Articulate’s interests regarding its property, including without limitation its intellectual property.

Authorized Resellers. We may share your PII and Usage Data with our authorized resellers and partners so that they can provide customers with timely, helpful information about our products and services. Our resellers are contractually obligated to abide by the Articulate privacy policy, preventing them from sharing your information with any other third parties. Several of our resellers are located in the EU; however, we have determined that our authorized resellers all have suitable safeguards to protect your information. For more information regarding our authorized resellers and their safeguards, request descriptions via our CONTACT US section below.

Marketing Partners for Purposes of Re-Marketing. We may share your information with 3rd party vendors for purposes of re-marketing. For a description of re-marketing and your opt-out rights, see the RE-MARKETING section below.

Your California Privacy Rights. Under California Law SB 27, California residents have the right to receive, once a year, information about third parties with whom we have shared information about you or your family for their marketing purposes during the previous calendar year, and a description of the categories of personal information shared. To make such a request, please send an email to the email address provided in our contact information below and include the phrase "California Privacy Request" in the subject line, the domain name of the Web site you are inquiring about, along with your name, address and email address. We will respond to you within thirty days of receiving such a request.

Your Nevada Privacy Rights. Under Nevada Law SB 220, Nevada consumers may submit a do-not-sell request of their personal information. Articulate does not sell the personal information of our customers. In accordance with the law, if you wish to submit a do-not-sell request, please do so by contacting us at [privacy@articulate.com](mailto:privacy@articulate.com) with the phrase “Nevada Privacy Request” in the subject line.

### Cookies and Opt-Out Procedures

Articulate may automatically collect Usage Data through the use of "cookies." Cookies are small text files a website uses to recognize repeat users, facilitate the user’s ongoing access to the site, and facilitate the use of the site. "Cookies" also allow a site to track usage behavior and compile site-usage information that will allow for the improvement of content.

##### Domain

| 

##### Cookie Name

| 

##### Purpose

| 

##### Persistence Duration  
  
---|---|---|---  
.360.articulate.com | _dc_gtm_UA-68728-1 | Google Tag Manager - logs detailed application usage data in Google Analytics. | 5 hours  
.360.articulate.com | _ga | Google Analytics - logs application usage data in Google Analytics. | 2 years  
.account.articulate.com | __stripe_mid | Stripe - used to aid in fraud detection for purchases. | 1 year  
.account.articulate.com | __stripe_sid | Stripe - used to aid in fraud detection for purchases. | 30 minutes  
.account.articulate.com | _dc_gtm_UA-68728-1 | Google Tag Manager - logs detailed application usage data in Google Analytics. | 5 hours  
.account.articulate.com | _ga | Google Analytics - logs application usage data in Google Analytics. | 2 years  
.account.articulate.com | _gid | Google Analytics - used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
.articulate-online.com | .ASPXAUTH | Encrypted ID for authentication to the server after signing in. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | ASP.NET_SessionId | Holds SessionID value and tracks current user's session state. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | AWSALB | Amazon Web Services Application Load Balancing - used to map the session to the instance. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | AWSELB | Amazon Web Services Elastic Load Balancing - used to map the session to the instance. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | CookieCheck | Session-level cookie to check for cookie support in browser. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | DefaultSort | Admin portal setting for default sorting of documents in document list page. | 3 years  
.articulate-online.com | DefaultSortDesc | Admin portal setting for sort preference name for documents in document list page. | 4 years  
.articulate-online.com | Enabled | Persistent cookie to check for cookie support in browser. | No expiration  
.articulate-online.com | LocalTime | Value of local time from client machine. | 24 hours  
.articulate-online.com | ReportEmailed | Session-level cookie to check if a report was emailed. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | ResetEmail | Session-level cookie set if customer resets password. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | UserKeyACCT_ID | Anonymous user tracking of public documents. | No expiration  
.articulate-online.com | VPDefaultSort | User portal setting for default sorting of documents in document list page. | 1 year  
.articulate-online.com | VPDefaultSortDesc | User portal setting for sort preference name for documents in document list page. | 2 years  
.articulate-online.com | WarnExpired | Session-level cookie set if account has expired. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | WarnOnHold | Session-level cookie set if account is on hold. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | __RequestValidation:DOCUMENT_ID | Session-level cookie set if document is cached. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate-online.com | _ga | Google Analytics - logs application usage data in Google Analytics. | 2 years  
.articulate-online.com | _gat_UA-68728-1 | Google Analytics - used to throttle request rate. | 1 minute  
.articulate-online.com | _gid | Google Analytics - used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
.articulate-online.com | acceptedEUConsent | Used to track if a user in the EU has consented to cookies. | No expiration  
.articulate.com | __ar_v4 | Google DoubleClick - used to track conversion rates for ads. | 5 years  
.articulate.com | __stripe_mid | Stripe - used to aid in fraud detection for purchases. | 1 year  
.articulate.com | __stripe_sid | Stripe - used to aid in fraud detection for purchases. | 30 minutes  
.articulate.com | _articulate_session_id | Enables single sign on across all Articulate applications. | 6 months (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | _articulate_user_email | Used for commenting in Review 360 | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate.com | _articulate_user_id | Session-level cookie used to enable single sign-on across all Articulate apps. | Cookie is removed when user logs out or when their Okta session is expired.  
.articulate.com | _articulate_username_prefill | Session-level cookie used to prefill username on id.articulate.com. | Cookie is removed when user logs out or browser is closed.  
.articulate.com | _dc_gtm_UA-68728-1 | Google Tag Manager - logs detailed application usage data in Google Analytics. | 5 hours  
.articulate.com | _ga | Google Analytics - logs application usage data in Google Analytics. | 2 years  
.articulate.com | _gat_UA-68728-1 | Google Analytics - used to throttle request rate. | 1 minute  
.articulate.com | _gid | Google Analytics - used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
.articulate.com | _mkto_trk | Marketo - allows a website to link visitor behavior to the recipient of an email marketing campaign, to measure campaign effectiveness. | 2 years  
.articulate.com | _post_widget_path | Returns user to their original location after registering or resetting their password via id.articulate.com | 7 days or upon return from completed login, registration, or forgot password flows.  
.articulate.com | _uetsid | Bing Ads - universal event tracking ID used to advertise via Bing. | 30 minutes  
.articulate.com | _vis_opt_exp_EXPERIMENT_ID_combi | VWO - used for A/B testing and generated when user reaches a particular combination to ensure user continues to see same variation on future visits. | 100 days (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | _vis_opt_exp_EXPERIMENT_ID_exclude | VWO - used for A/B testing and generated when a user has been excluded from a campaign. | 100 days (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | _vis_opt_exp_EXPERIMENT_ID_goal_GOAL_ID | VWO - used for A/B testing and generated when a goal is reached. | 100 days (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | _vis_opt_exp_EXPERIMENT_ID_split | VWO - used for A/B testing and generated during a split URL test. | 100 days (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | _vis_opt_s | VWO - used for A/B testing and detects if the user is new or returning to a particular campaign. | 100 days (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | _vis_opt_test_cookie | VWO - used for A/B testing and generated to detect if the user has cookies enabled in the browser. | Cookie is removed when browser is closed, or idle session times out (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | _vwo_uuid | VWO - used for A/B testing and generates a unique ID for every visitor to be used in the report segmentation feature. | 100 days (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | _vwo_uuid_v2 | VWO - used for A/B testing to analyze unique website visits via dynamic sampling. | 1 year (Note: We are no longer placing this cookie. They'll persist until expiration for existing users.)  
.articulate.com | cookiesEnabled | Stores whether the browser has cookies enabled. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out  
.articulate.com | country_code | Stores the 3-character country code for the website visitor. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.articulate.com | intercom-id-[app_id] | This is an Intercom cookie that enables Intercom live chat when a visitor is on our website. | 9 months  
.articulate.com | intercom-session-[app_id] | This is an Intercom session cookie that is used to track user sessions and store user conversation data. | 1 week  
.articulate.com | locale | Identifies the region of the visitor. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
.blogs.articulate.com | _dc_gtm_UA-68728-1 | Google Tag Manager - logs detailed application usage data in Google Analytics. | 5 hours  
.blogs.articulate.com | _ga | Google Analytics - logs application usage data in Google Analytics. | 2 years  
.blogs.articulate.com | _gid | Google Analytics - used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
.community.articulate.com | __ar_v4 | Google DoubleClick - used to track conversion rates for ads. | 5 years  
.community.articulate.com | _dc_gtm_UA-68728-1 | Google Tag Manager - logs detailed application usage data in Google Analytics. | 5 hours  
.community.articulate.com | _ga | Google Analytics - logs application usage data in Google Analytics. | 2 years  
.community.articulate.com | _gat_UA-68728-1 | Google Analytics - used to throttle request rate. | 1 minute  
.community.articulate.com | _gid | Google Analytics - used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
.id.articulate.com | ADRUM_BT1 | This is an AppDynamics server cookie that provides performance data to Okta for troubleshooting and service-level agreement compliance. It does not store or process PII. | < 1 min  
.id.articulate.com | ADRUM_BTa | This is an AppDynamics server cookie that provides performance data to Okta for troubleshooting and service-level agreement compliance. It does not store or process PII. | < 1 min  
.id.articulate.com | DT | This is an Okta cookie that is used for device-based and time-based, multi-factor identification on id.articulate.com. | 1 year 11 months 13 days  
.id.articulate.com | JSESSIONID | This is an Okta session cookie that is used to track user sessions. | Cookie is removed when user logs out or browser is closed.  
.id.articulate.com | oktaStateToken | This is an Okta cookie that supports users on the Articulate custom login page at id.articulate.com. | 4 min  
.id.articulate.com | proximity_{identifier} | This is an Okta cookie that enables an anti-phishing security image on id.articulate.com. | 11 months 13 days  
.id.articulate.com | sid | This is an Okta session cookie that enables single sign-on across all Articulate apps. | Cookie is removed when user logs out or browser is closed.  
.id.articulate.com | t | This is an Okta cookie that supports user interface themes on id.articulate.com. | Cookie is removed when user logs out or browser is closed.  
360.articulate.com | AWSELB | Amazon Web Services Elastic Load Balancing - used to map the session to the instance. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
360.articulate.com | __ar_v4 | Google DoubleClick - used to track conversion rates for ads. | 5 years  
360.articulate.com | __distillery | Wistia - used for stats tracking on Wistia video views across multiple sessions and/or page loads. | 1 year  
360.articulate.com | _gid | Google Analytics - used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
360.articulate.com | muxData | Wistia - used for tracking player health across all Wistia video embeds. | 20 years  
account.articulate.com | AWSELB | Amazon Web Services Elastic Load Balancing - used to map the session to the instance. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
account.articulate.com | _account-management_session | Used to store the current user’s membership (if applicable). | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
account.articulate.com | locale | Identifies the region of the visitor. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
account.articulate.com | selected_subscription_id | Session cookie that holds the subscription ID for the user. Primarily used for pointing the links in navigation to the correct team management and billing pages. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
articulate.com | AWSELB | Amazon Web Services Elastic Load Balancing - used to map the session to the instance. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
articulate.com | __atuvc | AddThis - stores an updated page share count. | 2 years  
articulate.com | __distillery | Wistia - used for stats tracking on Wistia video views across multiple sessions and/or page loads. | 1 year  
articulate.com | _active_360_user | Used to show 'Go to Articulate 360' button to logged out users. | 6 months  
articulate.com | _www-360_session | Articulate.com session cookie - used for persisting state during the visit. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
articulate.com | country_dropdown | Stores which country value to present to the user in website forms | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
articulate.com | liveagent_chatted | Salesforce - required for live sales and support chat functionality. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
articulate.com | liveagent_oref | Salesforce - required for live sales and support chat functionality. | 10 years  
articulate.com | liveagent_ptid | Salesforce - required for live sales and support chat functionality. | 10 years  
articulate.com | liveagent_sid | Salesforce - required for live sales and support chat functionality. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
articulate.com | liveagent_vc | Salesforce - required for live sales and support chat functionality. | 10 years  
articulate.com | muxData | Wistia - used for tracking player health across all Wistia video embeds. | 20 years  
articulate.com | rtp_segment | Enables real-time personalization of page content based on user profile. | 1 week  
blogs.articulate.com | __atuvc | AddThis - stores an updated page share count. | 2 years  
blogs.articulate.com | __atuvs | AddThis - enables visitors to share content with a range of networking and sharing platforms. | 30 minutes  
blogs.articulate.com | _ga | Google Analytics - logs application usage data in Google Analytics. | 2 years  
blogs.articulate.com | _gid | Google Analytics - used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
blogs.articulate.com | loved-ARTICLE_ID | Used to detect if user has clicked the "love" button on a specific blog post. | 1 day  
blogs.articulate.com | pixel_ratio | Used to detect retina or high DPI screens to show user higher resolution graphics. | No expiration  
community.articulate.com | AWSELB | Amazon Web Services Elastic Load Balancing - used to map the session to the instance. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
community.articulate.com | _community_session | E-Learning Heroes session cookie - used for persisting state during the visit. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
community.articulate.com | timezone | Lists the time zone. Example: "America/New_York". | 1 month  
community.articulate.com | timezone_offset | Returns the difference in client time zone and GMT in minutes. | 5 hours  
rise.articulate.com | AWSALB | Amazon Web Services Application Load Balancing - used to map the session to the instance. | Cookie is removed when user logs out, browser is closed, or idle session times out.  
rise.articulate.com | __distillery | Wistia - used for stats tracking on Wistia video views across multiple sessions and/or page loads. | 1 year  
rise.articulate.com | muxData | Wistia - used for tracking player health across all Wistia video embeds. | 20 years  
shush.articulate.com | _rack_session | Used for session management. | 30 days  
  
You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

### Remarketing

Articulate uses 3rd party vendor remarketing tracking cookies and pixels, including the Google Adwords tracking cookie and the NextRoll tracking pixel. This means we will continue to show ads to you across the internet, specifically on the Google Content Network (GCN) and through NextRoll’s network for remarketing. The third-party vendors, including Google, will place cookies on web browsers in order to serve ads based on past visits to our website. This allows us to make special offers and continue to market our products to those who have shown interest in them. **We do not remarket to users in the European Union**.

You may opt-out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the [Ads Preferences Manager](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/). You can opt-out of NextRoll’s remarketing by visiting the [Your Ad Choices website](https://youradchoices.com/control). Also, you can opt out of other third-party use of cookies by visiting the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/).

### Analytics

We may participate with third party analytics partners to monitor and analyze Web traffic and to keep track of user behavior on this site.

Google Analytics (Google) - Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google utilizes the data collected to track and examine the use of this site, to prepare reports on its activities, and to share them with other Google services.

Information collected: cookie and Usage Data. Visit Privacy Policy at <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies>. You may opt-out of the Google Analytics service with the Google's Browser Add-on that's available at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

### Your Rights

Use the CONTACT US section below for purposes of inquiring about your rights.

You may contact us to find out if we are processing your PII. If we are, you can ask us what Personally Identifiable Information of yours we hold and what we do with your data. If you would like, we can also provide you (or, where technically feasible, your chosen third party) with a copy of any PII that we hold about you, subject to a fee specified by law (not to exceed the reproduction cost of such document).

We may decline a request for access to or correction of PII in circumstances prescribed by the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) (Australia), and if we do, we will provide you with a written notice that sets out the reasons for the refusal (unless it would be unreasonable to provide those reasons) and the mechanisms available to you to make a complaint.

In addition, you may: (i) request access to and rectification or erasure of your PII, (ii) request restriction of processing your PII, and (iii) withdraw your consent at any time. If you provide a notice to us regarding your exercise any of the above rights, we will forward your notice to other authorized parties which are holding and processing your PII, where appropriate.

Privacy Shield Notice for Users in the European Union, United Kingdom, and Switzerland

Articulate Global, Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union, the United Kingdom and/or Switzerland to the United States. Articulate Global, Inc. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. In cases of onward transfer to third parties of data of EU, United Kingdom, and Swiss individuals received pursuant to the EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield, Articulate Global, Inc. is potentially liable. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Principles, Articulate Global, Inc. commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU, United Kingdom, and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact Articulate Global, Inc. at [privacy@articulate.com](mailto:privacy@articulate.com).

Articulate Global, Inc. has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to the EU Data Protection Authorities, United Kingdom Information Commissioner, and/or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC). Contact details for the EU data protection authorities can be found at [https://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm](https://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm). Contact details for the United Kingdom Information Commissioner can be found at [https://ico.org.uk/](https://ico.org.uk/). Contact details for the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner can be found at [https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/task.html](https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/task.html).

Articulate Global, Inc. will cooperate with the appropriate EU Data Protection Authorities, United Kingdom Information Commissioner and/or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner during investigation toward the resolution of complaints brought under Privacy Shield. These recourse mechanisms are available at no cost to you. The Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over Articulate Global, Inc.'s compliance with this Policy and the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. As a last resort, privacy complaints that remain unresolved after pursuing these and other channels may be subject to binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel to be created jointly by the US Department of Commerce, the European Commission, the United Kingdom Information Commissioner, and/or the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC).

### International Transfers

If you are from outside the U.S., understand that you are sending PII and Usage Data to the United States where our servers are located. That information may be then transferred within the U.S. or back out of the U.S. to other countries outside of your country of residence. Except for the U.S. and our certification for the Privacy Shield, these countries many not necessarily have data protection laws as comprehensive or protective as those in your country of residence; however, our collection, storage, and use of your PII and Usage Data will at all times be governed by this Privacy Policy.

### Links to Other Websites

This site may contain links to other websites operated by our joint venture marketing partners. If you do click on any of the links to their websites or accept any of their promotional offers, your click-through information and any information that you provide in the process of registration or purchase will be transferred to these sites. We have no responsibility or liability for the policies and practices of these sites. You should be careful to review any privacy policies posted on any of these sites before providing information to them.

### Children’s Online Policy

We are committed to preserving online privacy for all of its website visitors, including children. This site is a general audience site. Consistent with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we will not knowingly collect any information from, or sell to, children under the age of 13. If you are a parent or guardian who has discovered that your child under the age of 13 has submitted his or her personally identifiable information without your permission or consent, we will remove the information from our active list, at your request. To request the removal of your child's information, please contact our site as provided below under "CONTACT US", and be sure to include in your message the same login information that your child submitted.

### Do Not Track Requests

Some Web browsers incorporate a "Do Not Track" feature that signals to websites that you visit that you do not want to have your online activity tracked. Each browser communicates "Do Not Track" signals to websites differently, making it unworkable to honor each and every request correctly. In order to alleviate any communication error between browsers and website, we do not respond to "Do Not Track" signals at this time. As the technology and communication between browser and website improves, we will reevaluate the ability to honor "Do Not Track" signals and may make changes to our policy.

### Inquiries and Complaints

If you have any inquiries or complaints about our use of your PII, please let us know. You can contact us at any time via the CONTACT US section below, and we will take reasonable steps to investigate the complaint and respond to you.

You can also contact your national data protection supervisory authority in order to lodge a complaint against us.

### Contact Us

Contact us, as follows.

Articulate Global, Inc.  
244 5th Avenue, Suite 2960  
New York, NY 10001  
800-861-4880  

* * *

Material Modifications Since November 9, 2016: updates effective May 25, 2018 for purposes of compliance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation.
